ROBERT SMITH

Sales Business Development Specialist

Phone: (0123)-456-789 | Email: info@qwikresume.com | Website: Qwikresume.com

SUMMARY

An experienced Business Leader with a proven record of success managing strategic business initiatives in a Financial, Wholesale and Consumer arena. A creative self-starter that builds strong partnerships with key stakeholders. Call Center Management, Investor Relations, Client Management, Project Management, Large Sales Team Supervisory, Operational Management and International & Domestic Vendor Management experience.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Basic Japanese, Basic French.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Sales Business Development Specialist

ABC Corporation - 2010 - 2014

Key Deliverables:

- Designed and promoted into new position responsible for opening an untapped industrial distribution vertical market; developed procedures and key relationships that drove generation of \$10M+ in new revenue over 3-year period.
- Led all business development activities for new market, assigning accounts and collaborating with account representatives to ensure relationship management consistency and client satisfaction.
- Represented the company at national trade shows.
- Established 150+ new accounts that produced consecutive double-digit annual sales growth, peaking at \$4M.
- Created opportunities that grew the field sales team by 3 positions.
- Developed and managed the companys 2 largest clients (national accounts each at or near \$1M in annual sales) Motion Industries and Wolsley Industrial.
- Led an inside sales team of 5 to support the 500 branches of Motion Industries; designed a 32-page catalog for this client.

Business Development Specialist

Polygon US Corporation - 2008 - 2010

Key Deliverables:

- Glendale Heights, Illinois March 2013-Present Polygon Document Recovery Services recovers business retention documents, books, and photographs after a disaster
- Business Development Specialist Develop referral relationships in the 12 states of the Midwest, with Chicago being the main focus of development
- In this position, I work with insurance companies, organizations, and record managers to build a network of referral business when an emergency occurs
- Achievements Relocated to the Chicago area in August, 2014, and closed \$200K in sales in 2014

ROBERT SMITH

Sales Business Development Specialist

Phone: (0123)-456-789 | Email: info@qwikresume.com | Website: Qwikresume.com

- I am a member of five organizations in emergency services, insurance, and business retention to bring name recognition to the Chicago area
- Organize an open house event to clients
- Create the theme of the event, send out invitations, and maintain budget for the event.

EDUCATION

 Communication and Human Relationship Skills for Success - (DALE CARNEGIE TRAINING)